<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p005</paper_id>
  <session_id>s001</session_id>
  <flags>+</flags>
  <title>Tunable Acoustic Absorption Frequency through DSHS Height Control using the Brazil-nut and Reverse Brazil-nut Effects</title>
  <authors>오수민, 윤길호(한양대)</authors>
  <presenter>오수민</presenter>
  <session>음향 및 소음이론 [1]</session>
  <date>2026-05-27</date>
  <time>15:20~15:35</time>
  <venue>에메랄드홀</venue>
  <chair>정인지(표준과학연)</chair>
  <abstract>Sphere(°]S 분할 중공 -P), Acoustic metamaterial(2 메타물질) This study proposes an acoustic metamaterial that enables active tuning of the sound absorption frequency by controlling the position of a Double Split Hollow Sphere (DSHS). The Brazil-nut effect (BNE) and reverse Brazil-nut effect (RBNE) in granular materials are utilized to vary the height of the DSHS, thereby adjusting the resonance frequency. Under vertical vibration, granular convection and fluidization induce upward movement of the DSHS (BNE), whereas horizontal vibration suppresses convection, leading to downward movement (RBNE). This allows effective control of the DSHS position depending on the direction of vibration. Impedance tube experiments show that the absorption peak frequency shifts significantly with the DSHS position, which is also confirmed by simulations. Overall, these results show that DSHS position control enables active tuning of the absorption frequency for acoustic metamaterial applications. 80 | 1 —60 5 os &amp; ( 으 &amp; | 3 0.6 540 &apos; g BS — ——— p04 Top Middle Bottom 20 1 | ee | 2o2| | @ e Top ! @ Middle aa ik 5 가래 아아 ~ Bottom ae 5 10 15 20 25 30 400 500 600 700 800 900 1000 Time (s) Frequency (Hz)</abstract>
  <source_page>78</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p005.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>한양대</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Brazil-Nut effect(H2}4&amp; 효과)</keyword>
    <keyword>Reverse Brazil-Nut 6060(역브라질 효과) Double Split Hollow</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
