<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p058</paper_id>
  <session_id>s013</session_id>
  <flags>+*</flags>
  <title>QR-pivoting-based Primary DOF Selection for the General Model Reduction Methods</title>
  <authors>Robel Weldebrhan Hagos, 이승찬, 한재흥(KAIST)</authors>
  <presenter>Robel Weldebrhan Hagos</presenter>
  <session>기획   Dynamic substructuring</session>
  <date>2026-05-28</date>
  <time>09:30~09:45</time>
  <venue>그랜드볼룸[2]</venue>
  <chair>김진균(경희대)</chair>
  <abstract>Model order reduction (MOR) is essential for the efficient dynamic analysis of large-scale structural systems. The Craig-Bampton (CB) method remains the industry standard for component mode synthesis (CMS). However, it uses modal coordinates to represent the dynamics of interior degrees of freedom (DOFs) and does not directly retain physical coordinates at critical locations, such as sensor nodes or load application points, without transformation-based postprocessing. To address this limitation, general model reduction (GMR) and its extension (GMR+) preserve a subset of interior DOFs, referred to as primary DOFs, in physical coordinates. Nevertheless, the selection of these DOFs is typically based on heuristic criteria, which may lack robustness for complex geometries and broadband dynamic behavior. In this study, we introduce an approach for primary DOF selection by adapting QR factorization with column pivoting (QRCP) within the CMS framework. QRCP is widely used in experimental structural dynamics for optimal sensor placement. Here, the same principle is applied to numerical reduction: primary DOFs are selected by applying QRCP to the transposed modal matrix, identifying physical coordinates that best represent the dominant modal subspace. For global systems, the procedure is applied to the global mode matrix, and for substructured systems, to the fixed-interface normal modes computed in the standard CB process. By selecting DOFs associated with subsets of the modal basis, the method reduces spatial redundancy. When extended to GMR+, which includes the effect of residual flexibility modes, the approach further improves accuracy in higher-frequency regimes. Moreover, in substructuring applications, the additional computational cost due to QRCP is small, as it uses precomputed fixed-interface normal modes. The resulting reduced models retain physically interpretable DOFs without postprocessing, making them suitable for applications requiring localized response evaluation without back-transformation. + 교신저자; 한국과학기술원 항공우주공학과</abstract>
  <source_page>131</source_page>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>KAIST</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>General model reduction</keyword>
    <keyword>Primary DOFs selection</keyword>
    <keyword>QR factorization with column pivoting</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
