<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p072</paper_id>
  <session_id>s016</session_id>
  <flags>*</flags>
  <title>Bearing Fault Diagnosis under Variable Rotational Speeds via Multi-stream Fusion Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
  <authors>Altaf Hussain, Yong-Hwa Park(KAIST)</authors>
  <presenter>Altaf Hussain</presenter>
  <session>일반기계(기계시스템), 계측 및 모니터링 [3]</session>
  <date>2026-05-28</date>
  <time>09:15~09:30</time>
  <venue>릴리홀[1]</venue>
  <chair>전지현(원자력연)</chair>
  <abstract>융합), Variable Speed (7}&apos;4 속도) Deep Learning (@] #]*d) Nowadays, rotating machines are an essential part of modern manufacturing industries. Specifically, bearing fault identification using a single sensor is often insufficient. Therefore, researchers have increasingly adopted multisensory information fusion for more robust fault diagnosis. In this work, we propose a multi stream convolutional neural network (MSCNN) in which vibration, acoustic, and temperature signals are processed through independent convolutional neural networks for fault diagnosis. A feature level fusion strategy is developed to extract discriminative features from heterogeneous signal modalities. The proposed framework is evaluated on the University of Ottawa dataset and achieves a high performance of 91.67% in bearing fault diagnosis. These results demonstrate that MSCNN with feature level fusion effectively captures complementary information from different sensor modalities. The visual representation of the proposed framework is shown in Fig 1. To further analyze the performance of the MSCNN, a detailed ablation study is conducted to compare different fusion strategies, including data level fusion, weighted level fusion, and decision level fusion. The results are summarized in Table 1. Among all fusion methods, the proposed feature level fusion achieves the best performance because it integrates intermediate representations from heterogeneous signals in a more effective way. When combining all streams with feature level fusion, the model achieves the highest accuracy of 91.67%, along with improved precision, recall, and Fl score. These results indicate that feature level fusion enhances diagnostic reliability, although it introduces slightly higher model complexity. NEE te ISI Je AR Table 1. Performance of the proposed method. Hy level fusion : usion</abstract>
  <source_page>145</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p072.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>KAIST</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Bearing Fault Diagnosis (101% 결함 진단)</keyword>
    <keyword>Multi-Stream CNN (다중 스트림 CNN)</keyword>
    <keyword>Sensor Fusion (센서</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
