<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p137</paper_id>
  <session_id>s028</session_id>
  <flags>+*</flags>
  <title>Mimicking Graded Aortic Stenosis using a Mock Circulatory Loop</title>
  <authors>Adelle Ria Persad, 홍준기, 송현우, 송유리, 신해인, 이보미, 박용화(KAIST), 정재학(한국교통대)</authors>
  <presenter>Adelle Ria Persad</presenter>
  <session>기획   디지털헬스</session>
  <date>2026-05-28</date>
  <time>14:10~14:25</time>
  <venue>사파이어홀[1]</venue>
  <chair>이경태(부전전자)</chair>
  <abstract>시뮬레이터) Cardiovascular diseases like aortic valve stenosis (AS) involve the progressive narrowing of the aortic valve, forcing the left ventricle to generate significantly higher pressures to maintain cardiac output, which can eventually lead to heart failure. Current diagnostic tools, such 88 transthoracic echocardiography, serve as a &quot;snapshot&quot; method with high operational costs, while computational models often oversimplify complex fluid-structure interactions. To address the need for standardized physical platforms that can reproducibly simulate graded disease progression, this research re- engineered a mock circulatory loop (MCL) utilizing interchangeable silicone valves to represent different clinical stages of stenosis. The experimental cardiovascular simulator features a pump that serves as an artificial left ventricle and a 1:1-scale artificial human aorta. Aortic valve phantoms were fabricated from EcoFlex 0030 and SortaClear 18 silicones, designed with radially increasing thickness to replicate the stiffness of a &quot;Normal&quot; valve and four progressive stenosis stages, designated as Levels 1-4. Blood pressure waveforms were collected upstream and downstream of the valve across a comprehensive matrix of heart rates (40 to 80 bpm) and stroke volumes (50 to 80 mL). The transvalvular pressure gradients and the Effective Orifice Area (EOA) were used to validate the purely physical simulator hardware against clinical diagnostic criteria. The experimental results demonstrated a clear stepwise progression in transvalvular pressure gradients, increasing from a baseline mean of 6.89 mmHg under normal conditions to 84.71 mmHg for Level 4 stenosis, where peak left ventricular pressures exceeded 200 mmHg. Plotting the EOA against mean pressure gradients confirmed that the interchangeable valves correctly generated clinical markers; while the Level 2 valve acted as a transitional state, the Level 3 and 4 valves consistently clustered in the ‘Severe’ diagnostic region, producing an EOA of less than 1.0 cm? and mean gradients exceeding 40 mmHg. This validates the re-engineered simulator as a robust physical benchmark for replicating AS hemodynamics across diverse cardiac outputs, providing a reliable platform for the future development of non-invasive diagnostic tools. This work was supported by the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) grant funded by the Korea government(MSIT) (No. RS-2024-00350917). + 교신저자; 하국과학기술원 ＊ 칸국과학기슬원 , Se Reese 4 하국교통대학교 - 232 -</abstract>
  <source_page>245</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p137.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>KAIST</affiliation>
    <affiliation>한국교통대</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Cardiovascular Disease (심혈관 질환)</keyword>
    <keyword>Aortic Stenosis (]-E 42} 82H)</keyword>
    <keyword>Cardiovascular Simulator (4] 4 Zt</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
