<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p144</paper_id>
  <session_id>s030</session_id>
  <flags>+*</flags>
  <title>The Vibration Analysis Method of the Thin Chamber Equipment by Node Matching</title>
  <authors>Vu van Truong, 이호철, 김완진(한밭대)</authors>
  <presenter>Vu van Truong</presenter>
  <session>부문   미래융합기술</session>
  <date>2026-05-28</date>
  <time>15:35~15:50</time>
  <venue>그랜드볼룸[1]</venue>
  <chair>김완진(국립한밭대)</chair>
  <abstract>This study introduces an innovative and robust approach for the vibration analysis of thin chamber equipment, specifically applied to electrical switchboards using a node matching technique. To ensure structural stability under seismic excitation, the research proposes the integration of dampers and pivots as new anti-vibration devices (AVD). These devices are designed to mitigate vibrations caused by earthquakes and inertia forces resulting from the equipment’&apos;s mass. The core of the analysis involves a high-fidelity finite element (FE) model developed in Solidworks. The methodology employs a node matching approach to link complex components, such as the top cover casting parts and the AVDs. Each structural component was meshed using 8-node hexahedron elements, totaling 377,199 elements and 712,662 nodes, with a maximum mesh size of 30 mm to ensure the highest level of simulation accuracy. Experimental validation was conducted via shaker table tests to verify the dynamic characteristics. The results demonstrate a resonance frequency of approximately 6 Hz, with the AVDs reducing maximum relative displacement by at least 50%, proving the effectiveness of the node matching analysis in predicting and controlling vibrations for thin-walled industrial equipment. | ry 2 a - tone tg ~ 더 대 1: er 4 = 5 ! NE tet 82 19 Lh. . ‘ 기 10-7 10” 101 10? 로 — = Frequency (Hz)</abstract>
  <source_page>252</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p144.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>한밭대</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Earthquake</keyword>
    <keyword>Finite element analysis</keyword>
    <keyword>Node matching</keyword>
    <keyword>Vibration</keyword>
    <keyword>Seismic response.</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
