<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p172</paper_id>
  <session_id>s036</session_id>
  <flags>+*</flags>
  <title>A Large Language Model-aided Vision-based Framework for Structural Displacement Measurement</title>
  <authors>NGUYEN XUAN TINH, 윤형철, LAM PHAT TAI(충북대)</authors>
  <presenter>NGUYEN XUAN TINH</presenter>
  <session>부문   사회기반시설의 진동 해석, 실험 및 평가</session>
  <date>2026-05-28</date>
  <time>16:05~16:20</time>
  <venue>사파이어홀[1]</venue>
  <chair>정형조(KAIST)</chair>
  <abstract>Vision-based measurement(@7t 기반 계측), Large language 27ㅁ0086[(대규모 언어 모텔), ROI selection] 영역 선택). Accurate measurement of structural displacement is critical for effective monitoring and maintenance of civil infrastructure. In recent years, vision-based techniques have been adapted to structural displacement measurements due to their non-contact capabilities. These methods often utilize a defined region of interest (ROI) as the target for tracking displacement, which is typically detected either through a detection model requiring extensive training or manual selection by experienced users. This limits the widespread adoption of vision-based methods by non-expert users. To address this issue, this study proposes a large language model-aided vision-based framework for automated structural displacement measurement that assists non-expert users in measuring the displacement of structure. First, the vision-language understanding capability of LLMs is leveraged to identify and describe potential ROIs on the monitored structure that are suitable as targets for displacement tracking. Subsequently, an open-set object detector Grounding DINO is used to detect potential ROIs through their descriptions. From all detected ROIs, the optimum ROI is selected by the feature density analysis process. Finally, the displacement of the monitored structure is measured by inputting the optimum ROI into a Kanade-Lucas- Tomasi (KLT) tracker. The proposed method is validated through a_ series of experiments, demonstrating that the appropriate ROI can be automatically selected without additional model training or manual procedures, while still providing comparable measurement results. These results highlight the potential of integrating LLMs into vision-based structural monitoring workflow to enhance automation and practicality of displacement measurement framework. + 교신저자; 정회원, 충북대학교 토목공학부 교수 « 충북대학교 소프트웨어학부 박사과정</abstract>
  <source_page>280</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p172.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>충북대</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Structural health monitoring(7&apos;&gt;-2= 건전성 BEA)</keyword>
    <keyword>Structural displacement( 7 2= 변위)</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
