<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p212</paper_id>
  <session_id>s045</session_id>
  <flags>+</flags>
  <title>진동 기반 물질 전달 향상을 이용한 휴대형 망간 이온 센서</title>
  <authors>최도은, 박주형, 박현준, 김치현, 채경환, 김가영, 박대일, 조원준, 장다영, 김수빈, 강채영, 허은슬, 박진성(성균관대)</authors>
  <presenter>최도은</presenter>
  <session>기획   바이오 및 환경 센서</session>
  <date>2026-05-29</date>
  <time>08:40~08:55</time>
  <venue>사파이어홀[2]</venue>
  <chair>박진성(성균관대)</chair>
  <abstract>Manganese ions (Mn?*) are essential trace elements in biological systems; however, excessive exposure can cause neurological disorders and environmental contamination, particularly in drinking water. Therefore, the development of sensitive and portable detection systems for Mn?* monitoring is highly important. In this study, we developed a portable electrochemical sensor for manganese ion detection based on vibration-assisted signal enhancement. The electrode surface was sequentially modified by depositing graphite particles, followed by the electrochemical reduction of graphene oxide (GO) to improve electrical conductivity. Subsequently, a Nafion polymer layer was introduced as a cation-exchange membrane to enhance ion selectivity and preconcentration of Mn?*. The detection was performed using cathodic stripping voltammetry (CSV). During the deposition step of CSV, a coin vibrator was applied beneath the electrode to induce vibration, promoting mass transport and improving the accumulation efficiency of manganese ions on the electrode surface. As a result, the proposed sensor exhibited significantly enhanced electrochemical signals and achieved a limit of detection (LOD) of 489 pM. This vibration-assisted strategy provides a simple and effective approach for improving mass transport in electrochemical sensing systems and demonstrates strong potential for portable environmental monitoring applications.</abstract>
  <source_page>320</source_page>
  <pageImage>/paper-pages/p212.webp</pageImage>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>성균관대</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Electrochemical(417] 화학)</keyword>
    <keyword>Manganese( 7b)</keyword>
    <keyword>sensor(4l7])</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
