<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<paper>
  <paper_id>p245</paper_id>
  <session_id>s053</session_id>
  <flags></flags>
  <title>복소고유치의 이해와 응용 : Holset형 댐퍼의 동특성 규명</title>
  <authors>이수목(삼우ANC)</authors>
  <presenter>이수목(삼우ANC)</presenter>
  <session>진동, 동역학 및 제어이론 [4]</session>
  <date>2026-05-29</date>
  <time>10:55~11:10</time>
  <venue>사파이어홀[1]</venue>
  <chair>이수목(삼우ANC)</chair>
  <abstract>Lack of information and identification about the damping characteristics in vibrating system has led to approach mainly with the real eigenvalue analysis 1.6., natural frequency and mode shape, and appropriate modal damping model for forced response prediction. However in specific area like the marine engine application, the shafting system including the crankshaft and reciprocating parts is precisely described for the damping as well as mass inertia and stiffness based on background and experience of long engineering history. One of the methods to control the torsional vibration of engine crankshaft is to install the viscous damper on the front end of the shaft, one time called “Holset damper’ from the original developer and maker, now renamed over to other brand name. The Holset damper is composed of a single inertia (floating ring) and a damper (damping fluid between the ring and outer casing connected to main shaft) thus there is no static stiffness connection from the shaft. In real eigenvalue analysis sense the damper is absolutely detached regardless of damper specification. What is the reasonable way to take into account the dynamic effect of the damper in the (real) eigenvalue analysis? Of course there has been reasonable way such as transfer function method to overcome this contradictory situation and it sufficiently had been justified in the practical application. One very simple method, to the author’s memory, known from the practical side was to take the half of the ring inertia and attach it to the main shaft end. It is the concern and start point of this paper to confirm the validity of such on-practice method by the more direct and mathematical approach such as complex eigenvalue analysis which comprises mass, stiffness and also damping. For the analysis job, a typical model of 6 cylinder engine with load unit (propeller or generator) was assumed and a Holset damper with several ring inertia option and varying damper capacity was applied. The optimal damper size which gives maximum modal damping coefficient was chosen and its corresponding natural frequency was compared with that of no-damper model with attached mass inertia. The result showed equivalent mass inertia of the damper ranges 33%~47% of the original ring depending on damper ring size, which partly confirms the validity of existing practice but also partly reveals some considerable discrepancy. The numerical solution was implemented by state equation formulation for multi DOF complex eigenvalue analysis. Displacement (angle) and angular velocity were treated as independent vector variables and the order of differential equation was downgraded from 2&quot;4 MDOF to 1* 2MDOF differential equation. MATLAB eigenvalue function eig( ) is used. Natural frequency Damping coefficient Je ° | . i kk kes = ~~ EO A ! &lt; a ian os i 6 &apos; aC 초대 추대 HQ 조크 ~ sel ” 개 eo ee woe 자 400 S08 0 98 .</abstract>
  <source_page>387</source_page>
  <affiliations>
    <affiliation>삼우ANC</affiliation>
  </affiliations>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>complex eigenvalue analysis</keyword>
    <keyword>Holset damper</keyword>
    <keyword>equivalent mass inertia</keyword>
    <keyword>state equation</keyword>
    <keyword>MATLAB</keyword>
  </keywords>
</paper>
